Guide to the United Telegraph Workers Records WAG.144
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Collective Bargaining Materials
  - contract negotiations "New Valley"/Western Union, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bendix organizing., 1977 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Bendix negotiations; correspondence, notes, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Bendix contract drafts, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Bendix contract drafts, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Bendix negotiations notes #1, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Bendix negotiations notes #2, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Bendix negotiations notes #3, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Bendix contract negotiations correspondence (1979 80), 1980 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bendix, Decertification campaign concurrent with negotiations, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bendix contract Bulletins, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bendix contract with drafts, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bendix contract negotiations #1, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Bendix negotiations #2 (Salaried Employees Compensation and; benefits partial), 1980 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Bendix negotiations #3 notes, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Bendix/NTTF negotiations #1 correspondence, Bulletins, notes (1982 83), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Bendix/NTTF negotiations #2 (1983) (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Bendix contract negotiations #3 correspondence (1984), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Bendix contract negotiation Contract, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Bendix Contract Ratification Ballots 10/16/1983 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Bendix Pension Plan Revisions, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Bendix Pension Plan Revisions ERISA, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Bendix Correspondence in regard to negotiations, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Bendix Contract negotiations, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Bendix Decertification UTW, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Nationwide Food Services contracts Stipulations. correspondence, 1952, 1956, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Thomson and McKinnon (Brokers) contract negotiations, 1961, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - GTE; contract ratification, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Canadian Telecommunications DIV UTW; correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Div. UTW 1980 correspondence; (employee lists former Div. #43 National Railway CLB Election Canadian Labor Board) (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Canadian Telecommunication Div. correspondence, notes, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Canadian Telecommunication Union (Div. 5) UTW; correspondence notes, arbitrations, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union# 1; CP Rail, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; correspondence; notes (#2), 1982 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; #1, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Canadian Telecommunications 7 UTW; #2, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; #1, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; #2, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; #3, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union; Intervenor, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union, 1985, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union UTV; Press clips; Canadian Labor Board; other, 1928-1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Canadian Telecommunications Union UTW; Notes (dated and undated), 1928-1996 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Canadian Press UTW Div. contracts;; (1974,'76,'78,'80,'82,'84,'87), 1974-1987 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Canadian Press UTW Div. (contracts, other), 1928-1996 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Press UTW (contracts, 1986 89), 1986-1989 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - UTW contract UPI 1977 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - UTW contract UPI 1979 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - UTW contract UPI 1981 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - UTW contract; #1 and #2 UPI, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI Telegraph Workers; Correspondence, contracts, circulars, 1975-1979 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; Correspondence, notes, Pension Plan, 1980-1982 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; correspondence, notes, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; (January August) correspondence, notes, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - UTW Div #47 UPI; (September December) correspondence, notes, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - UTV Div #47 UPI; January June) correspondence, notes, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; (July December) correspondence, notes, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - UTW Div #47 United Press International (UPI); correspondence, notes, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; correspondence, notes (undated), 1928-1996 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; Wire Service messages (copies), 1928-1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI'; Wire Service messages (originals), 1928-1996 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - UTW Div. #47 UPI; Press clips (1983-85), 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - UPI Report, Feb 28, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - UTW Div. #14 Associated Press (AP); contract, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - UTW Div. #14 AP; contract, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - UTW Div. #14 AP; contract, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - UTW Div. #14 AP; contract, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - UTW Div. #14 AP; contract, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - UTW Div. #14 AP; correspondence, contract proposals, bulletins, resolutions, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - UTW Div #14 AP; correspondence, newsletters, resolutions j, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Western Union Div. Financial Data (Bargaining resolutions), 1960s (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Western Union #1 Pension Plan split; (Documents 1955 1983 Pension), 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Western Union Pension Plan split #2, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - UPI strike Telegraph Workers, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Western Union pre strike: bulletins, press, picketing/line organization, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Western Union strike pickets, line organization, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Western Union strike company correspondence, Ads, other, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Western Union strike bulletins, correspondence (March April), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Western Union strike bulletins, correspondence (April), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Western Union strike Fisher & Rudge/Danville Textile strike (same attorneys), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Western Union strike press releases, radio addresses, bulletins, other ACA, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Western Union strike National Press coverage, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Western Union strike bulletins, strike agreement (original signed copy, 5/23/52), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - 1962; 1966 strike ballots (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Western Union strike, 1928-1996 (Box 21, Folder 28)
- Series VIII: Joint Labor Management Task Force/QWL
  The union and the company's effort to manage the failing fortunes of the telegraph industry are reflected in this series. The Task Force and programs related to the Joint Labor Management program include correspondence, drafts, memos, working papers, and other materials related to the QWL program devised for Western Union The agreement between the company and the union to establish the Joint labor management Board was signed in October 1985. Materials date from 1985 to 1989.
  - National Joint Labor/Managements Board(NJL/MB)/UTW/Western Union correspondence, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - (January March) correspondence, memos, notes, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - (June July) correspondence, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - (August December) correspondence, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - (January May) correspondence, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - (June December) correspondence, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - minutes, NJL/MB, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - minutes, NJL/MB, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence; documents; training; sample, L/M QWL, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - ECR Associates, 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - ECR Associated Training; L/M BD. Western Union "Co operative Efforts:; Management, Union and Worker, Oct 17, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Training ECR Associates; "Dynamics of L/M Co operation", 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Training ECR Associates, 4/19/86; "Problem Solving" (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Western Union documents (press releases, corporate structure chart, financial and SEC reports), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - JT L/M BD documents (agreement, UTW/Western Union, structure, activities, operating procedures, notes), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - JL/MB assessment report/data summary (based on employee interviews), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Western Union assessment report NJL/MB draft letters to participants, 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Goals/communication program (correspondence, notes, drafts), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Goals/communication program July 29, 1986; October 1, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Task Force Recognition Program, correspondence; Part 1, 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Task Force Recognition Program, Part 2, 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Task Force Recognition Report, Part 2, 7/28/86, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Task Force Product Targeted Incentives (PC Sp) (UFCW sample), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Task Force SLIP (contract/maintenance/sales program), 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - '"Employee Suggestions" pre Quality of Work Life (QWL) program, 1928-1996 (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Series IX: Subsidiaries Case
  Legal materials relating to the "subsidiaries" case wherein Western Union maintained that its divisions constituted separate corporate entities. The records follow the case through the early correspondence, charges and complaints, from the NLRB to the U. S. Supreme Court.
  - Subsidiaries correspondence; 1972 (NLRB changes) (January August) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Subsidiaries correspondence/NLRB (September December), 1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Subsidiaries correspondence (NLRB changes/notes/bulletins), 1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Subsidiaries correspondence (NLRB amended complaint), 1974 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Subsidiaries correspondence (NLRB decision), 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Subsidiaries correspondence/Petition for Writ of Cert denied, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - UTW Bulletins notes (other), 1928-1996 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Western Union Research file (annual reports, notes, other), 1928-1996 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - FCC Western Union; subsidiaries, other, 1928-1996 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Legal Research file, 1928-1996 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - NLRB Hearing (transcript), Mar 18, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)(March 28) Hearing, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - NLRB Hearing (March 1974) part 3 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - NLRB 1974 (April 2) Hearing before Administrative Law Judge (transcript Part 4) (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - NLRB Brief on Behalf of Charging Party (UTW) (July 11, 1974) (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - NLRB Brief on Behalf of Counsel for General Counsel to Adm. Law Judge; July 12, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - NLRB Brief Western Union, Jul 29, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - NLRB Briefs; Decision; Western Union; UTW, Jan 1975-May 1975 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - NLRB Decision and Order Western Union; June 1, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Appellate Court briefs 1976, 1977, 1978 (for Petition, Reply Brief), 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Supreme Court, U.S. petition for/against Cert.), 1928-1996 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - CWA/UTW Court Case VU (correspondence, Briefs, Bulletins), 1985 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - CWA/UTW case Subsidiaries, Apr 1985 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - correspondence, notes, other CWAJUTW Subsidiaries Case, May 1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - CWA/UTW Subsidiaries correspondence, briefs, bulletins, Jun 1985-Jul 1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - CWA/UTW Case correspondence, judgements, bulletins, Aug 1985-Sep 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Report SEC, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Bankruptcy Proceedings (November 24) Corporation", 1993 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Bankruptcy Proceedings (January February 14), 1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Bankruptcy Proceedings "New Valley", Feb 16, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - '"New Valley", Feb 16, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Bankruptcy "New Valley", Feb 16, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "New Valley, Mar 1, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "New Valley", Apr 5, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - "New Valley", Apr 5, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - "New Valley", Apr 6, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - "New Valley", Apr 6, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "New Valley", May 24, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "New Valley", May 24, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "New Valley", May 24, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "New Valley", May 24, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "New Valley", 1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "New Valley", Jun 10, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - "New Valley", Jun 15, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "New Valley", Jun 15, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - "New Valley", Jun 20, 1994-Jun 23, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - "New Valley", Jul 26, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - "New Valley, Aug 3, 1994-Aug 19, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - "New Valley", Aug 22, 1994-Aug 26, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - "New Valley", Sep 2, 1994-Sep 12, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - "New Valley", Sep 16, 1994-Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - "New Valley", Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "New Valley", Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "New Valley", Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "New Valley", Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "New Valley", Sep 27, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "New Valley", Oct 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Subsidiaries files, research Data Services, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Data Services #2, 1928-1996 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Telegraph, exhibits and info. #1, 1928-1996 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Telegraph #2, 1928-1996 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Telegraph Terminal leasing DNP, 1928-1996 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Teleprocessing, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Western Union Computer Logistics Corporation and Gift America, 1928-1996 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Series X: Arbitration Appeals and Negotiations Records, 1947-1994.
  - Appeals Cases, Pension Split, Benefit Cases, Part-time Hours Dispute Settlement, 1954-1993 (Box 27)
  - Centralized Telephone Bureaus (CTBs), Grievance Log Sheet, Part-timers Stats Appeal, Legal Briefs, 1947-1994 (Box 28)
  - Legal Briefs, Strike Negotiations, Contract Negiotiations, 1952-1994 (Box 29)
  - Contract Negotiations, 1960-1994 (Box 30, Box 31, Box 32)
  - EBF Cases Nos. 1-73 to 5-89; Appeals Cases 19-79 to 222-82, 1973-1989 (Box 33, Box 34)
  - Appeals Cases, 1982-1994 (Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45)
- Series XI: Photographs, Charters and Badges
  This series contains photographs documenting the history of the Commercial Telegraphers Union/United Telegraph Workers from circa the early 1940s to the 1980s. Includes black-and-white and color group and documentary photographs from CTU/UTW conventions and meetings from the 1940s to the 1980s; black-and-white portraits and candids, with corresponding negatives, of union leadership and staff from circa 1973; circa 1940s small black-and-white prints from a CTU and AFL strike; an undated group portrait of the AFL-CIO Executive Council; and a portrait of Samuel Gompers.
  - Conventions and Meetings [Group Photographs], 1941-1979 (Box Tamiment Shared OS005)
  - First AFL-CIO Executive Council, Samuel Gompers Portrait, undated (Box Tamiment Shared OS005)
  - Group Photographs, Candids, Portraits -- CTU/UTW, circa 1970s-1980s (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Negatives [Union Officials, Staff], circa 1973 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Strike -- CTU, AFL, undated (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Union Officials -- CTU, circa 1973 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Union Officials -- CTU, 1973 (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - United Telegraph Workers [Group Photographs], undated (Box Tamiment Shared A004)
  - Oversized Photographs, 1943, 1945, 1947, 1948, 1953, 1969, 1971, circa 1960s (Box Tamiment Shared XOS003, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photographs, 1941, 1951, 1961 (Flat-file-folder 1, Tray 2)
  - CTU Charters, 1945, 1949 (Box Shared Tamiment 005, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, ephemera, 1907-1967 (Box Shared Tamiment 005, Folder 12)
  - Certificate of Affiliation, 1902-12-06 (Box Shared Tamiment 028, Folder 9)